<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal Development on Blog</title><link>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/tags/personal-development/</link><description>Recent content in Personal Development on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:10:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/tags/personal-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Depression</title><link>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/depression/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:10:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/depression/</guid><description>Culture and Environment Culture and environment where you eat could be one of the things that could trigger depression. It is also interesting because some of the climate could also be affecting our depression. For example, winter is most likely to trigger depression. One of the reasons is most of the winter people do not get enough exposure to sunlight which is one of the essential sources of vitamin D.</description></item><item><title>Finance Starter</title><link>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/finance_starter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 08:57:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/finance_starter/</guid><description>Focus on long term Never spend all your paycheck in one day.
Try to calculate all your expenses.
Assets and Liabilities Assets is something that will make money go into your wallet, liabilities is something that will make your money go away from your wallet.
Always focus on assets because this will affect you a lot in the long term.
Not all the liabilities are bad though, for example food, house rent, and insurance.</description></item><item><title>Learning as Developer</title><link>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/learning_developer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 07:17:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/learning_developer/</guid><description>Learning Fast Not to learn something on the book cover to cover.
Before learning something you must have a big picture first about what you wanna learn.
Define a goal, what parameter or finish line to make learning stick to the plan.
Not just learn only from one resource, different resources could provide different approaches so that some solution does not stagnance.
Doing some project that is related to the topic, play around with the topic that you wanna learn if you find yourself confused about certain things, go read or research from the resources that you already gather.</description></item><item><title>Be Productive</title><link>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/be_productive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 06:40:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://mohfahmi27.github.io/blog/be_productive/</guid><description>Prioritize Action Start to do some action rather than calculating all the decisions that are available. It’s always better to just take some action, because if we do not take action usually we tend to lose some of the opportunity to make you improve as a developer.
Always think about what could be the worst happen if you pick wrong decisions, usually things not going to be as bad as you might think.</description></item></channel></rss>